<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Simbols on Kungs</title><link>https://ViktorsTics.github.io/en/tags/simbols/</link><description>Recent content in Simbols on Kungs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ViktorsTics.github.io/en/tags/simbols/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anthem</title><link>https://ViktorsTics.github.io/en/p/himna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ViktorsTics.github.io/en/p/himna/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ViktorsTics.github.io/p/himna/maxresdefault.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Anthem" />&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The national anthem of Latvia, &amp;ldquo;Dievs, svētī Latviju!&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;God Bless Latvia!&amp;rdquo;) (1872), is a song by Kārlis Baumanis with lyrics written by him. It officially gained the status of the national anthem in 1920. The text was fixed in the law &amp;ldquo;On the National Anthem of Latvia&amp;rdquo; on February 19, 1998.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j7dCvf5RL24?si=OgPCvHhor1kif9dM" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Dievs, svētī Latviju!&lt;br>
Mūs&amp;rsquo; dārgo tēviju,&lt;br>
Svētī jel Latviju,&lt;br>
Ak, svētī jel to!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kur latvju meitas zied,&lt;br>
Kur latvju dēli dzied,&lt;br>
Laid mums tur laimē diet,&lt;br>
Mūs&amp;rsquo; Latvijā!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;God bless Latvia!
Our homeland grand and dear,
O, exalt Latvia,
O, bless it once more!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where Latvian daughters bloom,
Where Latvian sons hum,
There let us dance and cheer,
In our Latvia!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flag</title><link>https://ViktorsTics.github.io/en/p/flag/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ViktorsTics.github.io/en/p/flag/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ViktorsTics.github.io/p/karogs/Flag_of_Latvia.svg" alt="Featured image of post Flag" />&lt;p>The Latvian flag is carmine red with a horizontal white stripe in the middle. It was created in the 19th century, based on the description of the ancient Lettish or Latgalian flag in the Chronicle of Events, making it one of the oldest national flags still in use today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The unique carmine color of the flag was first officially described in a government document in 1922 to distinguish it from the similarly colored Austrian national flag.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the occupation of Latvia in 1940, using or storing this flag was punishable by law. The flag re-emerged publicly in the late 1980s, widely used during the Awakening, and its status as the national flag was restored on February 27, 1990.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background-and-interpretation">Background and Interpretation
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The two carmine red stripes symbolize the blood shed by Latvian soldiers over centuries for the freedom of their nation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The white stripe in the middle represents the honor, justice, and dignity of the Latvians, as well as their rights and laws.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The symbol of the Latvian state has a rich history, known for almost 800 years. The earliest written evidence of it dates back to the 13th century. The flag is mentioned in the Livonian Chronicle of Events as one of the flags of the Baltic peoples.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to legend, in one of the fierce battles, a Latvian commander was severely wounded and bled profusely. He was carried off the battlefield on a white cloth that became stained red with his blood. Only the middle stripe remained white, where the commander lay, who later died from his injuries. The soldiers, enraged by their loss, sought to avenge their leader&amp;rsquo;s death. They raised this cloth as a flag and, with renewed strength, went into battle, where they achieved victory. Since then, the red-white-red flag has been regarded as a national symbol of Latvia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to another version of the event, the blood of fallen enemies was collected in a large cauldron, where a white cloth tied to a spear was dipped. Thus, the entire cloth was stained blood-red, except for the spot where it was attached. This flag was used to intimidate opponents during battles.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In 1870, Latvian students found a description of the red-white-red flag in ancient chronicles and decided to adopt it as a national symbol.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The first Latvian national flag made of fabric was created by a simple teacher, Jānis Lapiņš. The sketch of the flag came to him along with thoughts about Latvian independence. The flag itself was sewn by Jānis’s bride, Marianna Straumane, in 1916.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cēsis History and Art Museum has preserved the first version of the flag. Its selection was not accidental. First, Cēsis is Jānis’s hometown. Second, the Livonian Chronicle of Events from 1279 states that soldiers with the red-white-red flag came from Cēsis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ViktorsTics.github.io/content/post/karogs/pirmskarogs.png"
loading="lazy"
>
In various regions of Latvia, Jānis’s flag underwent changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>images of a heart pierced by a sword were added, along with various ornaments;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the number and width of the white stripes were altered;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>other shades of red were used.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, it was the first version of the flag that was preserved and widely adopted.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>